What's up, guys?
>> Um, you know what? I I I guess you I've
never looked at it in seconds. I've
looked at it in hitches. Um, if a
quarterback hitches, he's he's got to
smell your breath. So,
>> what do you know about
>> uh relentless worker? Um, I joked with
him the other day. He's he's had those
guys in seven days a week about 12 hours
a day. So, he's been it's like, you
know, even a coach takes Friday night
and takes a wife out once in a while.
So, he's he's relentless in that regard.
>> Um,
in in in any situation, you're always
going to try to improve the roster and
you're always going to evaluate
everything that you do and uh so as as
far as what we're going to attack, we'll
keep that in house. But um but but
there's there's never going to be a
situation where we're not trying to
improve in any facet of football.
>> No. Um you know, if anything, it it
almost cost Dave the job. We interviewed
about eight linebackers coaches and um
you know, and but but Dave was clearly
the best one. He's coached some great
linebackers in this league and we're
excited to have him aboard.
How are you guys?
>> You know, there there's workouts,
there's uh talking ball with these guys.
There's a lot of things to be done. And
it's not just going to happen here.
There's there's uh pro days, there's 30
visits, there's conversations on Zoom
that we're going to be able to have with
these young men. And uh but it's
all-encompassing. It's not just their
ability to run a 40. um it's their their
ability to understand the game of
football and uh so there there's a lot
of things that that'll go on between now
and draft day.
>> Um
no that's a that's a really good
question. There's there's always going
to be a push for that. Um I know the the
league is working relentlessly to try to
figure it out. Uh do I have an answer
for you right now? I don't but um but I
know the people at the league office,
it's very important to them. I know it's
important to the owners of this league
and um and I know that uh they'll
continually continually try to figure it
out.
>> Um you know, San Francisco, uh it's a
championship organization. Uh
championship ownership, championship
head coach, championship GM,
championship everything. And um you know
just to be able to go back there having
been a head coach and to go back there
to piece the puzzle together of of of
what a championship organization look
like looks like and how it operates. Uh
I'm just grateful that I was given that
opportunity to do that again and um and
everything that I learned obviously
hopefully we can take it to this next
step.
>> Um well you know a lot of people know
this already. Gus is like a second dad
to me. um you know, he's had such an an
amazing impact on my life and and not to
mention he is one of the in my opinion
one of the better D coordinators in all
of football and uh so to be able to have
him on staff um uh especially through
this cycle where there was a lot of
competition for his for his services is
a blessing for for all of us. So
>> yeah, there um you know there there's a
lot of things you can do from a drill
standpoint. there's tape. Uh we have a
style of tackling that we've we
developed a while back ago with Pete
Carol over in Seattle that uh that has
been good to us. And um you know, we're
a shoulder leverage uh tackling team
that we took from rugby uh which takes
the head out of the game. And so there's
certain certain things that we'll teach
and we'll encourage and and there's
things that we'll rep constantly get
guys better at it.
>> Hey, Robert.
Um, I don't I don't know if fit's the
right word. You know, we um there's the
there a lot of guys in our system have
have taken the mold of different shapes,
sizes. Um, you know, for us, we just
look for guys who can play the game of
football and play it at a very very high
level. And uh, you know, there obviously
there are things that, you know, are
non-negotiables, but but those are very
uh rare and few in between.
Say it one more time.
>> Um,
well, there's it's a long answer. Um,
you know, it's there there's a lot of
things that you learn on the job. You
know, there's and I I've said it to a
bunch of people before. There's there's
no there's no manual for a first time at
anything you do. Like, there's no no
first time manual for you, too. And and
I'm sure you can look back at your first
day and and recognize that you're a lot
better today than you were back then.
And uh and I could say that I'm I'm much
more prepared now than I have ever been
and uh just looking forward to this
opportunity.
>> Say like a second player like
that fits into the scheme how this game.
>> Yeah. You know, with with a young man
like Fei, uh
it wasn't that he was just being
evaluated by three four teams. We
evaluated him as a 4-3 defensive end
whose hand was in the ground. And um you
know, for him, he's got all the talent
in the world. He's got length, he's got
speed, he's got pass rush ability, he
plays with violence. He's he's a good
football player. And uh you know, for
him, it's just going to be transferring
to getting your hand on the ground and
going vertical every snap rather than
having to think about coverages and all
that. So, um obviously there's going to
be a learning curve for him even in that
role. And and there's going to be a lot
of coaching and a lot of work on his
part uh to get himself better every
single day. And I think he's got the
mindset and the uh um the physical
ability to do that.
>> Hey Robert, on that note, some other
young players on the defense, a guy like
Devandre Sweat, a lot of people have
talked about how he fits in your
defense, a guy like Kevin Winston who
did a little big nickel last year.
That's something that you know you'll
work in those three safety packages. How
would you say a guy like Devandre Sweat
and Kevin Winston fit within your
defensive scheme?
>> Yeah. Um I'll address Sweat first. Um,
you know, we had a guy in 2000, I want
to say, I I I think it was 23, maybe 22,
uh, L. Woods, who's just as big, just as
fast, just as fleet of foot. Um, you
know, obviously it's going to be a
different, we're going to ask things of
him that are different than what he's
done in the past. But one things, one
thing he has shown on tape is he can get
numbers of numbers, which we we need our
D line to get be able to do. They need
to be able to run, and that is something
that he can do. Uh, he's a big man. He's
he's got much faster feet than people
realize. Um is it going to be easy for
him? It's not. It is a lot of work. Uh
it is it is a it is physically demanding
to play Dline in our system. Um but I do
think he's up to the task. Have had
great conversations with him and um I'm
excited to see him get to work.
>> Robert, in 2021, you became the first
head coach in NFL history. Now that you
took a headache role today, what does
that really mean to you and how do you
take that to Tennessee?
>> Um, no, I uh it's cool. I'm I'm forgive
me, I'm not very good at uh talking
about myself, but I I recognize the
impact in my community. Um, and I
appreciate uh appreciate the impact that
it has and um you know, if there's
anything I could ever do to pay it
forward to my commu community, I' I'd
always be there to do that. talked about
basketball. How do you break the roster
in terms of
>> um well well that's the thing is like
it's not just their ability to run a 40
Paul, you know, it's it's it's being
able to absorb the playbook and play
without play without thought. Um it's
going to be our job as coaches to be
able to extract every ounce of uh of
their physical ability. And uh that's
going to start in phase one of OTAAS.
Just getting them on the uh getting them
in the uh meeting rooms into the grass
and then in the practice and getting
them to see as many pitchers as they
can, get them as many reps as they can
to allow them to play as fast as they
possibly could. So again, it's it's a
it's a it's a team thing. It's not just
their ability to go out there and run
around and play fast. It's it's our
ability to allow them to unlock all
their physical ability as players.
agency. Do you prefer guys who can are
ascending players maybe to come in and
fulfill a three or four career contract
to fill holes now with maybe some older
guys just just to get the roster to
>> you're talking about free agency? Uh
you're looking every which way you can.
You know, you're not just going to put
you never want to limit yourself or put
yourself in a box with regards to what
you're looking for. Um if it's a young
guy, it's a young guy. If it's a
veteran, it's a veteran. And if they can
play the game of football and they can
improve your roster, you're you're
always going to take a peek at it.
>> Robert, as as we see the running back
position being devalued, where are you
as far as how important running back is
to offense, especially this year for a
guy like Jeremiah?
>> Yeah. Uh shoot, I just had a year with
Christian McCaffrey. I think he had over
400 touches, you know. So, um, you know,
if they're three down players and they
can impact the game and they can create
mismatches out, uh, out in the perimeter
as well as run the ball the way they do,
guys like Jir Gibbs, Christian, um, I'm
sure there's a few more. Um, they're
tremendous assets to the football team.
>> What conversations have you had
in the last month or two? How do you go
about developing a scheme?
Um, you know, you we we've had many
conversations and to be honest, you're
you're going to continue to push a
scheme and you're going to continue to
develop what you have. Um, and and like
I said, we're going to go through OTAAS,
we're going to go through training camp,
and no different than the players
learning us. We're going to learn our
players, and we'll continue to tweak our
uh scheme based on who we have and and
what they're capable of doing, and and
we're just going to keep fine-tuning it
until kickoff of week one. Robert, what
does a successful off season look like
specifically?
>> For Cam,
>> um, you know what, for for Cam, it's
it's it's always going to come down I
I've said I said it before, we're going
to take him back to his to his rookie
year, just to square one. You know, a
lot of these rookies when they get in
the uh when they join the team, you're
already halfway through phase two and
you're kind of playing uh uh you're in a
sprint to try to get them ready for for
training camp uh and for week one. We
can kind of take more of a marathon
approach with them where um you know,
we've got phase one, we've got phase
two, we've got our um we've got
different ways we can approach them
between now and uh uh week one to get
them prepared. So just taking those baby
steps, learning everything it takes to
be a quarterback, not just on the field,
but off the field. Uh so again, just
just him being his best and getting
better every single day will be good
enough.
>> How do you assess how do you assess the
standard?
>> Um you know, one thing I I appreciate he
does he he's he's in there every day.
He's working out and but he I don't
think there's a day that he goes by
without popping in saying hello. Uh, I
think he knows everybody in the
building's name, which I think is
impressive for a young quarterback, uh,
for a young man just in general. Uh,
he's very personable. He's, uh, it is
very important to him. That building is
very, very, very important to him. And,
uh, and you can tell that he's, he wants
to lead it. Um, and he's learning every
single day what it takes to be a leader.
And there's no doubt, I I've said it
before, a man who's built the way he is,
who's wired the way he is, who works the
way he does, um, it's very rare that
those people don't find success. So,
we're excited to get to work with them.
>> When you're evaluating the edge
position, how much is
>> uh again, that's really every position.
Um, arm length is always going to be
key, especially with a team like us that
that plays more of a zone style. Uh,
those uh those those long arms close uh
close up passing windows and do uh all
the different things that we ask them to
do. But, uh so it's really every
position. Arm length is always a big
deal.
Michael,
obviously somebody
who
was somebody
>> Yeah, Rudy was um you know, if Gus
didn't uh wasn't our coordinator, he was
going to be our coordinator here. Uh uh
outstanding human, outstanding
individual. He's going to bring so much
juice and energy. Uh he is as authentic
as authentic gets. He's elite with
regards to the pass game and the uh uh
uh from a defensive standpoint. and he's
walking into a situation where he's
already got an elite staff in place. Uh
guys like Tarver and their DB room and
their Dline coach, they're they're
outstanding and uh I think he's going to
be a fantastic addition. Um really proud
of him. Really excited for his outent.
>> Uh Mike Lafleur. Uh again, he's you know
what, an outstanding football mind. Um,
I I thought he did a great job when he
was when he was our coordinator. Thought
he's done a great job uh just evolving
his his uh um his ability to coach the
game and evolving his scheme with Shawn.
Uh I thought they did a great job over
there. Um obviously Stafford is a
quarterback, but what they did
offensively was was special, especially
this year. Um but uh but you're getting
a guy who understands the game of
football, understands people. Um uh
really looking forward to seeing how he
does.
How much does that player relate
in San Francisco?
>> I think I think some of it matters, you
know, but it's it's not the um it's not
the only thing uh um that matters.
There's there's relationships that were
built in the draft. There's uh through
the draft process. There's um there's
relationships that were built just
through time in the NFL. But uh but is
it part of it for sure? Is it the only
thing? It's not
>> relationships,
>> you know. Uh the best we can with the
rules of the uh with the offseason where
you know, communication is limited to
hello and and goodbye for the most part.
But uh uh like I said, Cam's been in
there every day. may have met been able
to meet up with Jeffrey a couple of
times, but uh I'm just looking forward
to getting these guys in here full-time
so we can continue to build our
relationships.
>> Um you know that there's
you're looking for a guy who can come in
and win football games for you if
something happens to the starter. You
know, a guy who's going to be a
tremendous uh uh who's going to support
the starter uh who's going to support
his team, who's going to prepare like a
starter. Um uh so you're you're you're
you're really looking for another
starter. So
>> earlier you guys
>> uh just met him had a really good
conversation with him the other day. Um
you know my my my one exposure to him
was back in 24 we played him in week
two. Uh I do think he's got tremendous
talent. He's got tremendous size,
tremendous arm strength. Uh um you know
again I'm I'm looking forward to him.
I'll tell you guys the same thing I told
him. Just attack this off season. and
have the best off season of your life
and compete your butt off and and let's
see what happens. But uh uh really
looking forward to him being part of
this football team.
>> Oh yeah. Um I know Houston's going to
punch you in the mouth. Um I know
Jacksonville's uh playing with a lot of
confidence and they've got a a head
coach and offense and a defense that uh
and a special teams unit that
complements each other very very well.
And I know Indianapolis before the
injuries was probably the the the bell
of the uh the um was was running the
division there for a minute. So it's it
is ultra competitive. Uh three
tremendous head coaches, three
tremendous staffs. Um so we're looking
forward to getting our opportunity to
compete. Thanks, coach.
>> All right, see you guys.